Out of tune they are going.
Non vanno a tempo.
They are going out of tune a little bit. Let them go in tune, you see?
Sono un po’ fuori tempo. Fateli andare a tempo, capito?
One should not go in…speak with heart, and speak with feelings,
Non si dovrebbe… Cantate con il cuore e con sentimento,
and should not be out of tune. They are out of tune, very much.
e non dovreste essere fuori tempo. Sono molto fuori tempo.
Do it properly. Now.
Fatelo bene. Ora.
Come along. Let’s have it again.
Avanti, rifacciamolo.
Must say in tune, in proper tune, you see?
Dovete cantare in sintonia, con la giusta sintonia, capito?
Just without tune if you go out… you play and then they should sing.
Se non andate a tempo, voi suonate e loro canteranno dopo.
Where are they? Those who are singing?
Dove sono i cantanti?
They should be there, you see, that’s why, they are not in tune with you.
Dovrebbero stare lì, vedete, ecco il motivo, non sono in sintonia con voi.
Come here, those who are singing. That’s better, that’s the reason.
I cantanti vengano qui. Ora va meglio, è questo il motivo.
You must sit with the musicians and sing in tune, alright?
Dovete sedervi insieme ai musicisti e cantare in sintonia, capito?
Not without tune.
Non fuori tempo.
Thus vibrations won’t come.
Così le vibrazioni non arriveranno.
Vibrations are not flowing. Is better to sing…
Ora non fluiscono. È meglio cantare….
not in tune, better sing like that.
non sono in sintonia, è meglio nell’altro modo.
They don’t know how to sing it.
Non sanno cantarlo.
Who has fixed this?
Chi l'ha composto?
Catching on the Sahasrara.
Il Sahasrara è bloccato.
Make it in Indian tune.
Cantate un motivo indiano.
So that’s a very not proper way. Let her sing,
Questo, quindi, non è affatto il modo giusto. Fate cantare lei,
she knows. Let her sing, she’ll tell you.
lei sa come fare. Lasciate cantare lei, vi dirà lei come fare.
You see, the vibrations could not My Sahasrara’s caught up.
Sapete, le vibrazioni non riuscivano... Il mio Sahasrara è bloccato.
Sit down, all of you sit down.
Sedetevi, sedetevi tutti.
These are mantras, this is not song, is mantras, you see?
Questi sono mantra, non una canzone, sono mantra, capite?
Are to be said with deliberations and understanding.
Devono essere pronunciati con comprensione e cognizione di causa.
You see, how it should be sung, not that like
Vedete, è così che si dovrebbe cantare, non come se foste
It's a deliberate thing, is mantras, you see?
È un mantra, è qualcosa di ben ponderato, capite?
Everybody has no right to sing mantras also.
Inoltre, non tutti hanno il diritto di recitare i mantra.
You must sing with deliberations.
Dovete cantare con piena cognizione di causa.
Now let us hear how they sing,
Ora ascoltiamo come cantano loro,
as I don’t want to catch again My Sahasrara.
perché non voglio avere di nuovo il Sahasrara bloccato.
Now which one, what one is they were singing?
Qual è la canzone che stavano cantando?
What is the one they were singing?
Quale canzone cantavano?
Yogi: The 10 names of Shri Lakshmi. Shri Mataji: Ah?
Yogi: ... I dieci nomi di Shri Lakshmi. Shri Mataji: Come?
Or nine…
Sahaja yogi: I dieci nomi di Shri Lakshmi. O nove…
Now. Do it slowly, steadily and without hurrying up.
Ora. Fatelo lentamente ma in modo fermo, e senza fretta.
And understanding what you are saying.
E con piena comprensione di ciò che state dicendo.
She rides on an elephant, not in an aeroplane.
Lei cavalca un elefante, non un aereo.
Sahaja yogi: Shri Mataji, shall we sing it in one part or we can
Sahaja yogi: Shri Mataji, dobbiamo cantarli in un’unica parte o possiamo
try to sing it in two parts? Shri Mataji: No, one part.
provare a cantarli in due parti? Shri Mataji: No, in un’unica parte,
Two parts is not good. That also is wrong. One part.
in due parti non va bene. Anche questo è sbagliato. In una parte.
One part and with deliberations, see?
In un’unica parte, ed in modo ponderato, va bene?
Every word should be clear cut.
Ogni parola dovrebbe essere scandita.
Then it is a mantras, you see? These are the words which are enlightened,
Inoltre sono mantra, capito? Sono parole illuminate,
and this is only very few people have this Adhikara,
e solo pochissime persone hanno questo Adhikara,
you see - you have, because you are sahaja yogis - to sing mantras.
di recitare i mantra, sapete; voi l’avete, poiché siete sahaja yogi.
Now let’s have it. Not in parts, sing it in one.
Ora facciamolo, cantate in un’unica parte, non in due.
ADYA LAKSHMI
ADYA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI ADYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
VIDYA LAKSHMI
VIDYA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI VIDYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI VIDYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
BHOGYA LAKSHMI
BHOGYA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI BHOGYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI BHOGYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
YOGA LAKSHMI
YOGA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI YOGA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI YOGA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
AMRUTA LAKSHMI
AMRUTA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI AMRUTA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI AMRUTA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SAUBHAGYA LAKSHMI
SAUBHAGYA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI SAUBHAGYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI SAUBHAGYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
GRUHA LAKSHMI
GRUHA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI GRUHA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI GRUHA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
RAJA LAKSHMI
RAJA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI RAJA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI RAJA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SATYA LAKSHMI
SATYA LAKSHMI
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
OM TWAMEVA SAKSHAT
SHRI SATYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI SATYA LAKSHMI SAKSHAT
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI ADI SHAKTI MATAJI
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
SHRI NIRMALA DEVYAI NAMO NAMAH
Good, beautiful, see the vibrations started flowing.
Bene, bellissimo, vedete, le vibrazioni hanno iniziato a fluire.
And now the meanings you know this.
Ed ora, i significati li conoscete.
Now, today when we are doing Lakshmi Puja
Oggi, mentre celebriamo il puja a Lakshmi,
all these are blessings on your chakras
tutte queste sono benedizioni ai vostri chakra
which are bestowed upon. So it has to be done in such a way
che vi vengono accordate. Quindi si deve fare in modo
that the deities should be happy and you should get all the blessings.
che le deità siano compiaciute e voi riceviate tutte le benedizioni.
See these are mantras. There’s a difference between a music and mantra.
Sapete, questi sono mantra. C’è differenza tra musica e mantra.
The mantras act on your chakras and open that part in you
I mantra agiscono sui vostri chakra ed aprono quella parte in voi,
and bestow that blessing of that mantra upon you.
concedendovi la benedizione di quel mantra.
This is the difference. Alright?
È questa la differenza. Capito?
So mantras should never be sung
I mantra non dovrebbero mai essere cantati
with a speed or just in a very superficial way.
in modo molto frettoloso o superficiale,
It has to be very deep with feelings and understanding.
ma con grande profondità, sentimento e comprensione.
Now do you know the meaning of all these Lakshmis?
Ora, conoscete il significato di tutte queste Lakshmi?
Can you tell them or should I tell them?
Sapete dirli o devo dirveli io?
Give Me the page.
Datemi il foglio.
Can I have My spectacles please? No, I can read.
Posso avere i miei occhiali, per favore? Anzi, no, riesco a leggere (senza).
Now first is the Adya Lakshmi. Adya is the one who is the Primordial,
Bene, la prima è Adya Lakshmi. Adya è la Lakshmi Primordiale, Primordiale.
As I told you about, that She came out of the Sea.
Come vi ho spiegato, Lei scaturì dal mare.
So that’s what we call Christ’s Mother was called as Mary, Maria,
Ecco perché la madre di Cristo fu chiamata Mary, Maria,
because She came from Marine. People don’t know why she was called as Mary.
perché scaturì dal mare. La gente non sa perché si chiamava Maria.
My name also is as you know, is Nira, meaning coming from water.
Il mio nome, come sapete, è anche Nira che significa uscita dall’acqua.
Then the second one is Vidya Lakshmi. She’s the one who teaches you
Poi, la seconda è Vidya Lakshmi. Lei vi insegna
the technique of handling the Divine Power.
la tecnica per usare il Potere divino.
Now this is to be understood very well. What is a Lakshmi?
Ora, occorre capire molto bene che cosa rappresenta Lakshmi.
Lakshmi is graciousness.
Lakshmi rappresenta la grazia.
So She teaches you how to use this power with graciousness.
Quindi Lei vi insegna ad usare questo potere con grazia.
Now, this is what is the blessing going to you so that you get the power
È questa la benedizione che vi arriva, così che ottenete il potere
of Adya Lakshmi by which you become like water
di Adya Lakshmi grazie al quale diventate simili all’acqua.
and what is the water? It has a cleansing power and it shines.
E cos’è l’acqua? Essa ha un potere purificatore e risplende.
Without water we cannot exist. It’s life.
Senz’acqua non possiamo esistere. Essa è vita.
So that’s the first blessing for you is that the face shines with Adya Lakshmi,
La prima benedizione per voi, dunque, è che con Adya Lakshmi il volto risplende,
that you become cleansing
voi diventate purificatori
and that you can sink all that is material
e potete affondare tutto ciò che è materiale,
– all that is light can float on you.
mentre tutto ciò che è leggero può fluttuare su di voi.
Now. The Vidya Lakshmi is the one as I told you gives you knowledge
Ora, Vidya Lakshmi, come vi ho detto, è Colei che vi dona la conoscenza,
– knowledge how to handle the Divine Power graciously.
la conoscenza di come usare con grazia il Potere divino.
I’ll give you an example. I’ve seen many people
Vi farò un esempio. Ho visto molte persone
when they give bandhans, it’s such a crude way, that.
che quando si danno un bandhan lo fanno in modo molto rozzo, così.
No, it is not to be done. It’s a Lakshmi’s blessing.
No, non si deve fare. È una benedizione di Lakshmi.
So how you do it, very carefully. You see me, how I give always.
Va fatto con molta attenzione. Osservate come io lo faccio sempre.
I never do that way! I cannot! With respect.
Non lo faccio mai in quel modo - non posso! – ma con rispetto.
With grace. She represents the respect part of it.
Con grazia. Lei rappresenta il rispetto.
And that you get – that knowledge. How to do it gracefully.
Ed è questo che voi ottenete, questa conoscenza di come farlo con grazia,
Everything to be done gracefully – in a manner that looks gracious.
di come fare ogni cosa con leggiadria, in un modo che appaia pieno di grazia.
See, some people who talk have no grace.
Sapete, alcune persone non hanno grazia nel parlare.
Some people who give knowledge of Sahaja Yoga
Anche certe persone che diffondono la conoscenza di Sahaja Yoga
also have no grace and they talk in a disgraceful manner.
non hanno grazia e parlano in modo disdicevole.
So all the grace – how to use
Quindi, tutta questa grazia nell’usare
the knowledge of the Divine is given by Vidya Lakshmi.
la conoscenza del Divino, è data da Vidya Lakshmi.
Now Saubhagya Lakshmi. She’s the one who gives you good fortune.
Ora, Saubhagya Lakshmi è Colei che vi accorda la buona fortuna.
Good fortune doesn’t mean money, but it means the grace of money.
Buona fortuna non significa denaro, ma indica la grazia del denaro.
Many people have money but it’s like money on a donkey.
Molti hanno denaro, ma è come se a possedere il denaro fosse un asino.
You do not find any grace in that person.
In loro la grazia è assente.
Or it doesn’t also mean, Saubhagya doesn’t mean
Saubhagya non significa soltanto denaro, ma indica tutta la buona fortuna.
All the good luck in everything in a very gracious manner, is this.
Tutta la buona fortuna in ogni cosa, con gran leggiadria. È questo.
To you the blessings so that you also are blessed
Sono benedizioni per voi, affinché sia voi
Amruta Lakshmi. Amrut means the one that is the nectar.
Amruta Lakshmi. Amrut significa il nettare.
If you take that you will not die. Means eternity.
Bevendolo, non morirete. Significa eternità.
So She’s the one who gives you the life of eternity.
Lei, dunque, è Colei che vi concede la vita eterna.
Gruha Lakshmi. Gruha Lakshmi is the deity of the family
Gruha Lakshmi. Gruha Lakshmi è la deità della famiglia,
- the one who is the deity of the family. Now, any housewife
la deità della famiglia. Ora, non tutte le donne di casa
need not be Gruha Lakshmi. She can be a shrew.
sono necessariamente delle Gruha Lakshmi. Possono essere delle megere.
She can be a horrid thing.
Possono essere orribili.
The deity of the household
Se la deità della casa risiede in voi, siete una Gruha Lakshmi,
Then there is Raja Lakshmi. She is the one who gives grace to the kings.
Poi c’è Raja Lakshmi. Lei concede grazia ai re.
If the kings behave like servants, then they are not called as kings.
Se i re si comportano da servi, non si chiamano re.
They have to behave in a dignified manner. The dignity, the majesty of the king
Devono comportarsi con dignità. La dignità, la maestà del re
comes from the Raja Lakshmi in him.
nasce dalla Raja Lakshmi in lui.
But a sahaja yogi need not be training.
Ma un sahaja yogi non ha bisogno di allenarsi.
He walks very straight in a very stately manner.
Egli cammina ben eretto, con un portamento davvero maestoso.
In his movements he’s stately. He’s very majestic in handling people.
È regale nei gesti. È assolutamente regale nel trattare le persone.
He’s very gracious in doing anything
È colmo di grazia nel fare qualsiasi cosa,
in such a manner that people think, “Oh, here comes a king.”
tanto che la gente pensa: “Oh, ecco che arriva un re”.
Satya Lakshmi. That is,
Satya Lakshmi. Significa
that you get the awareness of truth, but apart from that
che ottenete la consapevolezza della verità, ma oltre a ciò…
– the awareness of truth is there
vi è consapevolezza della verità,
but to put this truth forward in a gracious manner.
ma anche la capacità di esprimere questa verità con grazia.
Not to, “Now this is the truth – have it!”. Not like that!
Non è dire: “Bene, questa è la verità, prendi!”. Non così.
Don’t have to hit people with the truth.
Non dovete urtare la gente con la verità.
You have to put it in a flower and give it to them. That is Satya Lakshmi.
Dovete metterla in un fiore e porgerla agli altri. Questa è Satya Lakshmi.
Of course the all Lakshmi Tattwas are
Certo, tutti i principi di Lakshmi sono
the parasympathetic powers within us
i poteri del nostro sistema nervoso parasimpatico,
but they are actually expressed in our brain.
ma in realtà si esprimono nel nostro cervello.
Brain is the Virata.
Il cervello è il Virata.
Is the Vishnu when He becomes the Virat – the Akbar.
È Vishnu quando diviene il Virata, l’Akbar.
So all His powers are, specially these powers are in the brain.
Tutti i Suoi poteri, specialmente questi, risiedono nel cervello.
So, the brain itself spontaneously behaves
Pertanto, il cervello stesso si comporta spontaneamente
in such a manner that people think that this is a special type of a personality.
in modo tale da far pensare alla gente di trovarsi
Then we have got
Abbiamo poi
Bhogya Lakshmi, by which we know how to enjoy.
Bhogya Lakshmi, grazie alla quale riusciamo a gioire.
A sahaja yogi always knows how to enjoy everything.
Un sahaja yogi riesce sempre a gioire di ogni cosa.
He doesn’t…
Lui non…
The sahaja yogi is never worried type. Anything he can enjoy.
Il sahaja yogi non è mai preoccupato. Riesce a gioire di tutto.
Once, we climbed a very steep place, called Palitana.
Una volta scalammo un luogo molto scosceso chiamato Palitana
It was about 6 miles above – like that - as if walking for 6 miles – climbed up.
per circa sei miglia. Ci arrampicammo camminando per sei miglia.
I was not tired at all when I saw the carvings.
Non mi sentivo per niente stanca, quando vidi le sculture.
And I was telling my son-in-law, “See
Dissi a mio genero: “Guarda,
every tail of the elephants is made differently.”
ogni elefante ha la coda fatta in modo diverso!”.
He says: “Mother I’m panting here. How can you see the tails of the elephants?”
E lui: “Mamma, io sono qui senza fiato.
It is because I can enjoy. You should be able to enjoy anything.
Il motivo è che io so gioire. Voi dovreste gioire di tutto.
Now supposing you see something absurd – ridiculous.
Supponiamo che vediate qualcosa di assurdo, di ridicolo.
Then you should laugh and enjoy. This is a ridiculous thing, you see? Is absurd.
Allora dovreste ridere e divertirvi. È ridicolo, sapete, è assurdo.
But one should not get angry with somebody because somebody is absurd or funny.
Ma non ci si dovrebbe adirare con qualcuno che è assurdo o strano.
But should make it enjoyable.
Al contrario, dovreste prenderlo come una cosa divertente.
So that is the greatest, I think one of the greatest blessings
Ritengo dunque che il fatto che Lei vi dia il potere di gioire delle cose,
- that She gives you the power to enjoy things.
sia la più grande, una delle benedizioni più rilevanti.
Otherwise whatever you may try people don’t enjoy anything
Diversamente, in qualsiasi modo si provi, la gente non gioirà di nulla
because they have become so ego-oriented that nothing goes into their heads.
poiché è diventata così piena di ego che non le entra niente in testa.
They have to be tickled here with the electrodes.
Occorre farle il solletico qui con gli elettrodi.
Yoga Lakshmi – the one who gives you Yoga.
Yoga Lakshmi. Lei vi accorda lo Yoga.
That power is within you. That is the power of Lakshmi within you,
Questo potere è in voi, ed è il potere di Lakshmi dentro di voi
means you give others the yoga.
grazie al quale voi date lo Yoga agli altri.
Now when you give the power
Ora, quando date il potere
of yoga to others, I mean when you use your power of yoga,
dello Yoga agli altri, intendo dire quando usate il vostro potere di Yoga,
then you don’t behave like a monkey or a donkey
non vi comportate come una scimmia o un asino
or a horse, but you do it with grace.
o un cavallo, ma lo fate con grazia.
Do it in such a manner that it is very gracious.
Lo fate in un modo che risulta pieno di grazia.
That is what you call (searches English term for word in Sanskrit)...
È ciò che chiamate…(cerca equivalente inglese per il termine sanscrito, ndt)
Sahaja yogi: Gently? Shri Mataji: Ah. In a gentle,
Sahaja yogi: Con gentilezza? Shri Mataji: Ah. In modo gentile,
dignified, majestic way.
dignitoso, maestoso.
Gentle, dignified, majestic way
Gentile, dignitoso, maestoso:
– three words (in English) for one word (in Sanskrit). So this is what it is.
tre parole (inglesi) per renderne una (in sanscrito). Dunque è questo.
And now when you have sung it in this manner,
Ed ora che avete cantato in questo modo, vi è stato concesso questo potere.
Now even if you want you cannot behave indecently.
Adesso non potete comportarvi in modo indecoroso neanche volendo.
You are fixed.
Siete fissi.
Alright. Thank you very much. So mantras should be said
Va bene, molte grazie. I mantra, dunque, dovrebbero essere pronunciati
deliberately with understanding. Like the one you have made one poem – song.
in modo ponderato, con comprensione. Come quella canzone che avete composto.
In that, you sing in a proper way.
In quella, cantate nel modo giusto.
Never just go on: “Shri–this, Shri-that, Shri…”.
Mai limitarsi a cantilenare: Shri-questo, Shri-quello, Shri...
No, no, no. It’s like taking a role call of the Lakshmi’s,
No, no, no. È come seguitare a chiamare le Lakshmi:
“Are you there, are you there, are you there”?. Like that.
“Ci sei? Ci sei? Ci sei?”. Così.
So now do it in a very deliberate manner and with due respect and graciousness
Ora, dunque, fatelo con grande cognizione di causa
because specially with the Lakshmi’s thing you have to be extremely gracious.
Infatti, specialmente con ciò che riguarda Lakshmi,
You have to use very gentle words and gentle tunes and gentle notes.
Dovete usare parole molto dolci, melodie garbate e note delicate.
All right.
Va bene.